A Guide to theJames I. Robertson Papers 1862-2001 (bulk 1981-2001) Ms.1994.021
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
James I. Robertson Jr. Papers
1862-2001
bulk
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Robertson, James I., Jr.
Ms.1994.021
22 Cubic Feet 37 boxes
Research notes, manuscripts, typescript drafts, working copies and galley proofs for books and articles written by Virginia Tech's Alumni Distinguished Professor of History James I. Robertson Jr., 1982-2001. Also contains a small set of general materials which includes items related to the preservation of lands adjacent to Manassas National Battlefield Park.
376 containers; 22 cu. ft.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Robertson Papers were donated by James I. and Elizabeth Robertson in two accessions: May 1996 and July 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
James I. "Bud" Robertson Jr., Civil War historian, author and Alumni Distinguished Professor of History at Virginia Tech, was born in Danville, Virginia, in 1930. After graduating from Randolph-Macon College (B.A., 1955), Robertson obtained his M.A. (1956) and Ph.D. (1959) at Emory University and served as a teaching fellow (instructor in history) at Emory from 1958 to 1959. From 1959 to 1961, Robertson served as editor of Civil War History, a quarterly journal published by the University of Iowa. In 1961, he was appointed executive director of the National Civil War Centennial Commission by President John F. Kennedy and served until 1965, supervising the national observance of the Civil War centenary. Robertson served as professor of history at the University of Montana from 1965 until 1967, when he joined the faculty of Virginia Tech. He served as History Department head from 1969 to 1977, and was C. P. Miles Professor of History from 1977 to 1992. He became Alumni Distinguished Professor of History in 1992.
Robertson has authored many award-winning scholarly books on Civil War-related topics, including Soldiers Blue and Gray (1988) (nominated for the Pulitzer Prize in History), Civil War Virginia: Battleground for a Nation (1991), General A. P. Hill: The Story of a Confederate Warrior; and Stonewall Jackson: The Man, the Soldier, the Legend (1997). He has also written two books for younger readers: Civil War! America Becomes One Nation (1992) and Standing Like a Stone Wall: the Life of General Thomas J. Jackson (2001). Robertson has been a contributing author and editor for several other works; his articles, too numerous to list here, have appeared in many encyclopedias, Civil War magazines and historical society journals.
Scope and Content
The papers of James I. Robertson Jr., Civil War historian, author and Alumni Distinguished Professor of History at Virginia Tech, span the dates 1862 to 2001 and are comprised of writings and general materials. The writings consist largely of materials (research notes, manuscript drafts, typescript drafts and galley proofs) related to the writing and publication of a portion of Robertson's books and articles between 1982 and 2001. The small number of general materials includes items related to the preservation of lands adjacent to Manassas National Battlefield Park and a few manuscript drafts for various speeches made by Robertson.
Arrangement
Series I: Writings, 1981-2001, Boxes 1-34
This series contains research notes, manuscript and typescript drafts, edited working copies, master copies and galley proofs for 10 books and two articles published between 1982 and 20041. The series is arranged by the works' chronological order of publication. The materials for each work are arranged in chronological order, according to the dates supplied. (Where dates were unavailable, the sequence was determined by comparing the different drafts.) The drafts include revisions made by Robertson and others (identified in the individual folder descriptions, when possible). The series' holdings are not comprehensive and do not include every draft of every work. The subseries for Jackson & Lee, for example, contains only a typescript draft of a single chapter.
Series II: General Materials, 1862-1996, Box 35
All materials not directly related to the writing and publication of Robertson's works are assembled within this series, which includes items pertaining to the preservation of lands adjacent to Manassas National Battlefield Park, manuscript drafts for various speeches made by Robertson, a list of articles written by Robertson and assorted ephemera. Materials are arranged by function.
Series III: Oversize Materials, 1982-1990, Box 36
This series consists of oversize galley proofs which were too large to be filed in Series I. Items in this series are arranged according to the order in which they would have been filed had they remained in Series I.
Missing Title
Barringer, Paul B. Narrative of Pilgrimage to Cedar Mountain and Manassas Battlefields, September 4-5, 1968 ([Richmond?: s.n., 1968?]) E472.183 N377 1968 Civil War Spec
Johnston, J. Ambler. Echoes of 1861-1961 ([Richmond]: privately printed, 1970) F227 .J6 1970 c.3 Civil War Spec
Johnston, J. Ambler. The Civil War 1861-1865 in Arkansas and Missouri: Notes on the April, 1967 Trip of the Chicago Civil War Round Table ([Richmond]: Distributed by the Virginia State Penitentiary, 1967) E470.4 .J647 1967 c.2 Civil War Spec
Wilshin, Francis. Manassas (Bull Run) National Battlefield Park, Virginia (Washington D.C., 1957) Docs I 29.58:15/2 Civil War Spec
Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Civil War; Faculty; University Archives; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Robertson, James I., Jr.; Robertson, James I., Jr.
- Series I: Writings
  - Civil War Sites in Virginia: A Tour Guide (1982)
    - Typescript draft, n.d.; Photocopy (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Final copy with publisher's comments, 1981 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Master copy, [1982?] (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Galley proof, [1982?]
      Scope and Contents note
      See Oversize Materials, Box 36
  - General A.P. Hill: The Story of a Confederate Warrior (1987)
    - Research notecards (Box 2-8)
      Introduction; Pre-1848; Post-Mexican War; Coming of War; Williamsburg; Promotion to Brigadier General; Mechanicsville; Gaines' Mill; Frayser's Farm; End of Seven Days' Campaign; Cedar Mountain; Second Manassas; Antietam Creek; Fredericksburg; Chancellorsville; Gettysburg; Bristoe Station; Wilderness; Petersburg; 1865
    - Original typescript draft, [1985?]; 2 folders (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Original typescript draft, [1985?]; 2 folders (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Preface - First draft, [1985] (Box-folder 9:3)
      with corrections by Elizabeth Robertson, Beth Brown, Richard Harwell and Random House
    - Chapter 1 - First working copy, Dec 29 [1985] (Box-folder 9:4)
      with corrections by Richard Harwell
    - Chapter 1 - Final working copy, Apr 18 1986 (Box-folder 9:5)
    - Chapter 2 - First draft, Jan 5 1986 (Box-folder 9:6)
    - Chapter 3 - First working copy, Feb 12 1986 (Box-folder 9:7)
      with corrections by Beth Brown
    - Chapter 3 - Final copy, n.d. (Box-folder 9:8)
    - Chapter 4 - Copy of original typescript draft, n.d. (Box-folder 9:9)
      with corrections by Ed Raus
    - Chapter 4 - First draft, Apr 8 1986 (Box-folder 9:10)
      with corrections by Robert Krick and Ed Raus
    - Chapter 4 - Third draft, May 8 1986 (Box-folder 9:11)
    - Chapter 5 - Typescript draft, Apr 7 1986 (Box-folder 9:12)
      with corrections by Dennis Frye
    - Chapter 5 - First working copy, Mar 28 1986 (Box-folder 9:13)
    - Chapter 5 - Second draft, Apr 11 1986 (Box-folder 9:14)
    - Chapter 6 - First draft, Apr 24 1986 (Box-folder 9:15)
      with corrections by author
    - Chapter 7 - Copy of original typescript draft, [Apr 1986] (Box-folder 10:1)
      with corrections by Elizabeth Robertson, Harry Pfanz and Beth Brown
    - Chapter 8 - First draft (incomplete), May 16 1986; with corrections by Robert Krick (Box-folder 10:2)
    - Chapter 9 - Copy of original typescript draft with corrections, n.d. (Box-folder 10:3)
    - Chapter 9 - First draft, Jun 6 1986 (Box-folder 10:4)
      with corrections by Beth Brown and Chris Calkins
    - Complete draft, Jul 15 1986 (Box-folder 10:5)
      with author's final corrections; 4 folders
    - Complete draft, Aug 29 1986 (Box-folder 10:6)
      with publisher's final corrections; 2 folders
    - Setting copy I, [1986]; 4 folders (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Master galleys, Dec 15 [1986]; 2 folders (Box-folder 11:2)
    - Master copy, Jan 23 [1987]; 2 folders (Box-folder 12:1)
    - Galley proof, [1987]; 2 folders (Box-folder 12:2)
    - Setting copy II, [1987]; 2 folders (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Unbound signatures, 1987 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - Soldiers Blue and Gray (1988)
    - Outline, n.d. (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Rough typescript, n.d.; 2 folders (Box-folder 13:2)
    - First draft, 1987; 3 folders (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Revisions (chapters 6, 8-9 only), 1987 (Box-folder 13:4)
    - Second draft, [1987]; 2 folders (Box-folder 13:5)
    - Third draft (chapter 1 only), Sep 22 1987 (Box-folder 14:1)
    - Final draft, May 13 1988 (Box-folder 14:2)
      with publisher's comments
  - "The Boy Artillerist: Letters of Colonel William Pegram" (1990)
    - Original typescript draft with author's corrections, [1990] (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Civil War Virginia: Battleground For a Nation (1991)
    - Outline, [1989?] (Box-folder 14:4)
    - Original draft, 1989; 2 folders (Box-folder 14:5)
    - First draft, 1989 (Box-folder 15:1)
    - First draft, 1989 (Box-folder 15:2)
      with corrections by Ludwell Johnson (chapters 1-5 only)
    - First draft, 1989 (Box-folder 15:3)
      with corrections by Charles Roland
    - Second draft, 1990 (Box-folder 15:4)
      with corrections by Gary Gallagher
    - Third draft, 1990 (Box-folder 15:5)
    - Final draft, 1990 (Box-folder 15:6)
      with publisher's comments; 2 folders
    - Final draft, [1990] (Box-folder 15:7)
      incorporating publisher's revisions
    - First galley proofs, May 15 1990 (Box-folder 15:8)
    - Final galley proofs, Aug 24 1990
      see Oversize Materials, Box 36
  - "Stonewall Jackson: Molding the Man and Making a General" (1992)
    - Typescript draft, n.d. (Box-folder 16:1)
    - Publisher's layouts, 1992 (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Civil War! America Becomes One Nation (1992)
    - Typescript text of The Civil War (published 1963), n.d. (Box-folder 16:3)
    - Original manuscript, n.d. (Box-folder 16:4)
    - Original typescript draft, n.d. (Box-folder 16:5)
    - First draft - Original version, Nov 13 1988; 2 folders (Box-folder 16:6)
    - First draft - Revised version, Dec 8 1988 (Box-folder 16:7)
    - Working copy, [Feb 1989?] (Box-folder 16:8)
    - Draft sent to publisher, Feb 16 1990; 2 folders (Box-folder 17:1)
    - Final draft, May 1991 (Box-folder 17:2)
    - First galley proofs, Oct 1991 (Box-folder 17:3)
    - Second galley proofs, Nov 1991 (Box-folder 17:4)
    - Map labels, n.d.
  - The Civil War's Common Soldiers (1994)
    - First draft, 1993 (Box-folder 17:5)
    - Second draft, 1993 (Box-folder 17:6)
    - Final draft, 1993 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Jackson & Lee: Legends in Gray (1995)
    - Typescript draft of chapter 3 ("Virginia Orphan"), n.d. (Box-folder 17:8)
  - Stonewall Jackson: The Man, The Soldier, The Legend (1997)
    - Original working draft - Introduction, 1993 (Box-folder 18:1)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 1, 1993 (Box-folder 18:2)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 2, 1993 (Box-folder 18:3)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 3, 1993 (Box-folder 18:4)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 4, 1993 (Box-folder 18:5)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 5, 1993 (Box-folder 18:6)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 6, 1993 (Box-folder 18:7)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 7, 1993 (Box-folder 19:1)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 8, 1993 (Box-folder 19:2)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 9, 1993 (Box-folder 19:3)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 10, 1993 (Box-folder 19:4)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 11, 1993 (Box-folder 19:5)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 12, 1993 (Box-folder 19:6)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 13, 1993 (Box-folder 20:1)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 14, 1993 (Box-folder 20:2)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 15, 1993 (Box-folder 20:3)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 16, 1993 (Box-folder 20:4)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 17, 1993 (Box-folder 20:5)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 18, 1993 (Box-folder 20:6)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 19, 1993 (Box-folder 20:7)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 20, 1993; 2 folders (Box-folder 20:8)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 21, 1993 (Box-folder 21:1)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 22, 1993 (Box-folder 21:2)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 23, 1993 (Box-folder 21:3)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 24, 1993 (Box-folder 21:4)
    - Original working draft - Chapter 25, 1993 (Box-folder 21:5)
    - Working draft - Chapter 3, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 21:6)
      with corrections by Lowell Reidenbaugh
    - Working draft - Chapters 5-7, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 21:7)
    - Working draft - Chapters 8-9, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 21:8)
    - Working draft - Chapter 10, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 21:9)
    - Working draft - Chapter 11, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 21:10)
    - Working draft - Chapter 12, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:1)
    - Working draft - Chapter 13, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:2)
    - Working draft - Chapter 14, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:3)
    - Working draft - Chapter 15, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:4)
    - Working draft - Chapter 16-17, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:5)
    - Working draft - Chapter 18, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:6)
    - Working draft - Chapter 19, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:7)
    - Working draft - Chapter 20, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:8)
    - Working draft - Chapter 21, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:9)
    - Working draft - Chapter 23, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 22:10)
    - Working draft - Chapter 23, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 23:1)
    - Working draft - Chapters 24-25, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 23:2)
    - First draft - Chapters 1-2 (Box-folder 23:3)
    - First draft - Chapters 3-4 (Box-folder 23:4)
    - First draft - Chapters 5-6 (Box-folder 23:5)
    - First draft - Chapters 7-8 (Box-folder 23:6)
    - First draft - Chapter 9 (Box-folder 23:7)
    - First draft - Chapter 10 (Box-folder 23:8)
    - First draft - Chapter 11 (Box-folder 23:9)
    - First draft - Chapter 12 (Box-folder 24:1)
    - First draft - Chapter 13 (Box-folder 24:2)
    - First draft - Chapters 14-15 (Box-folder 24:3)
    - First draft - Chapters 16-17 (Box-folder 24:4)
    - First draft - Chapter 18 (Box-folder 24:5)
    - First draft - Chapter 19 (Box-folder 24:6)
    - First draft - Chapter 20 (Box-folder 24:7)
    - First draft - Chapter 21 (Box-folder 24:8)
    - First draft - Chapter 22 (Box-folder 24:9)
    - First draft - Chapter 23-24 (Box-folder 25:1)
    - First draft - Chapter 25, Abbreviations and Bibliography (Box-folder 25:2)
    - First draft - Chapters 5-6 (Box-folder 25:3)
      with corrections by unidentified person
    - First draft - Chapters 7-8 (Box-folder 25:4)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 1-2, n.d. (Box-folder 25:5)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 3-4, n.d. (Box-folder 25:6)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 5-6, n.d. (Box-folder 25:7)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapter 7, n.d. (Box-folder 25:8)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 8-9, n.d. (Box-folder 26:1)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 10-11, n.d. (Box-folder 26:2)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 12-13, n.d. (Box-folder 26:3)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 14-15, n.d. (Box-folder 26:4)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapter 16, n.d. (Box-folder 26:5)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 17-18, n.d. (Box-folder 26:6)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapter 19, n.d. (Box-folder 26:7)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapter 20, n.d. (Box-folder 26:8)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapters 21-22, n.d. (Box-folder 27:1)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Chapter 23, n.d. (Box-folder 27:2)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Endnotes, Foreward-Chapter 12 (Box-folder 27:3)
    - Draft submitted to publisher - Endnotes, Chapters 13-25 (Box-folder 27:4)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 1, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 27:5)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 2, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 27:6)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 3, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 27:7)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapters 4-5, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:1)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapters 6-7, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:2)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 8, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:3)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 9, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:4)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 10, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:5)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 11, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:6)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 12, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:7)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 13, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 28:8)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 14, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:1)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapters 15-16, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:2)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapters 17-18, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:3)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 19, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:4)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 20, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:5)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 21, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:6)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapter 22, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:7)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Chapters 23-25, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:8)
    - Publisher's laser proof with corrections - Bibliography, Feb 1996 (Box-folder 29:9)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 1-2, [1996] (Box-folder 30:1)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 3-5, [1996] (Box-folder 30:2)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 6-8, [1996] (Box-folder 30:3)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 9-11, [1996] (Box-folder 30:4)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 12-14, [1996] (Box-folder 30:5)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 15-17, [1996] (Box-folder 30:6)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 18-19, [1996] (Box-folder 31:1)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 20-21, [1996] (Box-folder 31:2)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 22-24, [1996] (Box-folder 31:3)
    - Working proof [?] - Chapters 25, Abbreviations and Bibliography, [1996] (Box-folder 31:4)
    - Working proof [?] - Endnotes, Chapters 1-13, [1996] (Box-folder 31:5)
    - Working proof [?] - Endnotes, Chapters 14-25, [1996] (Box-folder 31:6)
    - Working copies for Abbreviations and Bibliography sections, [1996] (Box-folder 31:6)
    - Galley proof (author's copy) - Chapters 1-5, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 32:1)
    - Galley proof (author's copy) - Chapters 6-10, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 32:2)
    - Galley proof (author's copy) - Chapters 11-14, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 32:3)
    - Galley proof (author's copy) - Chapters 15-19, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 32:4)
    - Galley proof (author's copy) - Chapters 20-23, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 32:5)
    - Galley proof (author's copy) - Chapters 24-25, Bibliography and End Notes, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 32:6)
    - Galley proof (master copy) - Chapters 1-5, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 32:7)
    - Galley proof (master copy) - Chapters 6-10, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 33:1)
    - Galley proof (master copy) - Chapters 11-15, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 33:2)
    - Galley proof (master copy) - Chapters 15-19, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 33:3)
    - Galley proof (master copy) - Chapters 20-23, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 33:4)
    - Galley proof (master copy) - Chapters 24-25, Bibliography and End Notes, Jul 15 1996 (Box-folder 33:5)
    - Revisions to galley proof - First set, Sep 25 1996 (Box-folder 33:6)
    - Revisions to galley proof - Second set, Dec 3 1996 (Box-folder 33:7)
    - Revisions to galley proof - Third set, Dec 23 1996 (Box-folder 33:8)
    - Index draft with corrections, Oct 21 1996; 2 folders (Box-folder 34:1)
  - Standing Like a Stone Wall: The Life of General Thomas J. Jackson (2001)
    - Manuscript (with publisher's revisions) - Chapters 1-7, [2001?] (Box-folder 34:2)
    - Manuscript (with publisher's revisions) - Chapters 8-end, [2001?] (Box-folder 34:3)
  - Soldier of Southwestern Virginia: the Civil War Letters of Captain John Preston Sheffey (2004)
    - Seager transcripts and notes for 1861 letters (Box-folder 35-1)
    - Seager transcripts and notes for 1862 letters (Box-folder 35-2)
    - Seager transcripts and notes for 1863 letters (Box-folder 35-3)
    - Seager transcripts and notes for 1864 letters (Box-folder 35-4)
    - Seager transcripts and notes for 1865 letters (Box-folder 35-5)
    - Seager maps and illustrations (Box-folder 35-6)
    - Seager essays, 1997-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 35-7)
    - Sheffey family genealogy notes and sources, 1982-2002, n.d. (Box-folder 35-8)
    - Robertson transcripts of Jan-Jun 1861 letters, n.d. (Box-folder 35-9)
    - Robertson transcripts of Jul-Dec 1861 letters, n.d. (Box-folder 35-10)
    - Robertson transcripts of 1862 letters, n.d. (Box-folder 35-11)
- Series II: General Materials
  - Manassas Battlefield Park Preservation, 1988; 2 folders (Box-folder 36-1)
  - Drafts of assorted speeches by Robertson, n.d. (Box-folder 36-2)
  - List of articles by Robertson, 1957-1991 (Box-folder 36-3)
  - Ephemera - "La Mode Illustree" prints, 1862; 2 items (Box-folder 36-4)
  - Ephemera - assorted postcards from Abingdon, Virginia and envelopes addressed to Vicki Heilig, 1989-1996 (Box-folder 36-4)
- Series III: Oversize Materials
  - Civil War Sites in Virginia: a Tour Guide - galley proofs, [1982?] (Box-folder 37-1)
  - Civil War in Virginia: Battleground for a Nation - final galley proof, 1990 (Box-folder 37-2)
  - Civil War! America Becomes One Nation - galley map labels, n.d. (Box-folder 37-3)
  - "Bold Reconnaissance: General Stonewall Jackson at Brawner's Farm, Battle of Second Manassas, August 28, 1862", 2000 (Box-folder 38-1)
    limited edition signed print by Brian Kraus